All right. So, in the last video, we
talked about concatenation and formatted
strings. I just want to show you a
reference that shows you all of the
things you can do with strings. So, what
I've done is I've gone to W3 Schools. If
you just Google W3 Schools, it'll be
probably the first website that pops up.
Um, this has a whole bunch of references
for a whole bunch of languages, whole
bunch of programming stuff. But if you
want to reference the JavaScript stuff,
you'll come here to JavaScript, and then
you can see all of this JavaScript
information. Um, so there's JavaScript.
You could click on strings and this will
show you how to create a string. And
this is a very helpful resource. One of
the things I want to point you to under
JavaScript strings, there's a JavaScript
string reference. If you click on
JavaScript string reference, it'll show
you everything that you can do with a
string. Um, so in this video I am going
to talk about something specific you can
do with the string. And we're going to
talk about this substring method. So
click on that if you are following along
with me. And it says what it does is it
sub extracts a substring from the text.
So if you want to get just part of the
text, you don't want all of the hello
world, you just want part of the hello
world, then you can use substring.
Um if you come down here, it says it
takes in a starting position and it
takes in an ending position up to but
not including the ending position. Um,
and if you don't give it the ending
position, then it'll just give you the
rest of the string. So, let's go see
this in action. Come over here to your
Visual Studio Code. We're going to get
rid of everything we had last time. And
we're going to type the text Bruce Wayne
is Batman.
And we're going to put that into a
variable. So, let's create a variable.
We'll say let my text equal and then the
text Bruce Wayne is Batman.
Okay, let's say I just want to pull out
the word Bruce.
Um, I'm going to create another variable
and I'm going to say let um
short text
equal.
And then now I'm going to slice off part
of this string. So I want a substring.
So if I come over to my code, I come
over to the reference guide, it says the
way you get a substring is you take the
variable name and then you do dot
substring. So coming back over to our
code, our variable is called my text. So
we'll say my text dot substring
and if we put the opening parenthesy, it
says it needs a starting number which is
it says it's zerobased index. That means
that the first letter is going to be
zero and then everything on from that is
going to be an increasing number. So it
means this capital B in Bruce is in
position zero. Computers start counting
from zero. And so when they made
JavaScript they made it so that it also
started counting from zero. If you
remember computers store information is
0 and one. Therefore a logical starting
place for counting for a computer is
zero. So our strings start counting at
zero as well. So, if we want to grab the
letter B, then we need to start at the
zero position. And then if we want to
grab all the way through the end of
Bruce, then we've got to count out how
many positions we're moving over. So,
we'll say, comma, and then it says now
where is the zerobased ending number.
So, if
B is 0, R is 1, U is 2, C is 3, and E is
4. So if we do a substring of 0, 4, then
that should give us the word Bruce.
Let's just see if that worked. So we'll
say alert and then we'll say short text
and we'll save that.
If we go live, we'll pop over to our
website and you can see it said B R U C.
And it looks like I must have miscounted
because it chopped off the E. If we come
back, we can see why that is. So if we
put the parenthesis on our substring, it
says what's the starting number? I said
zero. What's the ending number? If you
read closely, it says if um up to but
not including the character indicated by
the end. So I said 0 was B, one was R,
two was U, three was C,
four was E. I said four, but it doesn't
include the last number. So what I want
to do is I actually want to say go to
the space which is position five and
then it doesn't include that. So then
this will include the text just the text
Bruce. If we save that and we come over
here now we've got our full string for
Bruce. Um
if we wanted to start at a different
position let's say we just wanted to get
Batman. We would have to find where the
text of Batman started. So, it's zero. 1
2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15. It
looks like it is in the 15th space.
Um, we could count out to figure out
where the n comes in this string or
um the hint said that if you leave it
off, it'll just return the rest of the
string. So, if we if you leave off the
end portion. So, if we run this, we
should expect to see Batman. So, we'll
save our code. We'll come back over to
our website and we get the text Batman.
And that is how you use Substream.